so hi everyone this is Joe Brewer here
this morning I'm working on creating a
detailed outline for bioregional
regeneration course and I wanted to talk
to you a little bit about why I'm doing
this and how the people that I'm working
with really need it and it's been
difficult to put together so far so
first of all you're all aware of the
global crisis that were in a lot of
people frame it in ways around up
pulling carbon dioxide out of the
atmosphere and you know maintaining
biodiversity and you know the other
pieces that are really difficult to wrap
your head around from a systemic point
of view it turns out there is a huge
body of thinking and practice that goes
back literally decades about how to do
design work and restoration work at a
regional scale and this is everything
from cleaning up the water in an entire
watershed managing the hydrological
cycle of a mountain range trying to
preserve and maintain the health of
fisheries and marine estuary of the
ocean people have worked on these very
complex challenges for a long time in
different parts of the world and I was
surprised to learn just about two weeks
ago that the place I grew up in
southwest Missouri was the first place
that a bio regional conference was
organized in the late 1970s around the
shared cultural identity and landscape
of the Ozarks these people were doing
this work in the 1970s when I was just
one year old so I'm more than 40 years
old now this has been going on for
decades what we're trying to do now is
take this bioregional way of thinking
that looks at how human societies are
organized and in particular how they
might potentially organize themselves to
manage landscapes in their local areas
that the work being done in this in this
approach has mostly been project-based
small-scale and difficult to achieve
cooperation so you might find someone
who's bought a twenty acre piece of land
changed the way they do farming from
industrial chemical based using
petroleum and pesticides and herbicides
to instead doing some kind of no-till
organic gardening or organic farming or
you might see some group that's taken a
piece of land and set it aside for
conservation and done agroforestry and
reforestation things like this you know
even this kind of work which is
literally happening in thousands of
places around the world most people
don't know about it certainly it's not
recognized as a global movement so what
we are doing is trying to address two of
the really critical pieces that are
missing for going from decades of
thinking on regional scale work and
thousands of projects that are at a
smaller scale and there are two pieces
that have been missing or that are not
developed well enough for us to achieve
larger scale impacts one of them is the
focus on education when a group of
people set out to take a piece of land
and start to regenerate it they don't
have other people around who have the
knowledge and skill to just bring in and
put them to work on the land and help
them you know on that piece of land to
regenerate it there just aren't enough
people trained to do this so even if we
were to have a kind of World War two
mobilization for millions of people
those people would have to be retrained
and re-educated to do this because there
just aren't enough people that know how
so we found there's a huge missing piece
and the education and training of people
the second missing piece is the
institutional coordination at the
regional scale and what I mean by this
is bringing together a diverse set of
people who live and work in a
place convening them helping them to map
out the ecosystems the social systems of
food production and energy production
transport the history of the culture and
how it's been managed in that place
throughout time all of that coordination
and mapping has not been done in a
systematic way in most places and also
to coordinate and facilitate
decision-making creating scenarios of
the future managing and planning how
those scenarios relate to any kind of
shared agenda that a group of people in
the place might create and try to enact
and then that leads very quickly into
questions of funding and jurisdiction or
who has the responsibility and the
empowerment to make different kinds of
decisions how do they relate to systemic
problems in the region there's a whole
body of knowledge tools and frameworks
for how to do this but they're not
generally taught which gets back to the
education piece and they're not
structured as organizational capacity
which is the institution building piece
so these two pieces together have been
missing in my work in the last two
months with the regenerative communities
Network I have gotten to have a
first-hand account of some of the best
bioregional work being done on earth not
all of it but just the sampling of it
there's really a lot going on and as I'm
talking to people in different places
and learning what they're doing I see
that these two missing pieces are
absolutely essential and so I have been
tasked with the responsibility to help
design a curriculum that begins to train
people in bio regional scale
regenerative design so there are a lot
of people already doing education in
this area and not pretending that this
is the first or the only effort but it
is an effort recognizing these two
missing pieces while at the same time
seeing that this regional scale work is
emerging
ten times with decades of previous work
in many places around the world and let
me just give two examples to show how
deep this is happening if you look at
the area of Devon in England which
includes the town of Totnes those of you
who know the transition town movement
well know that this is a place that
permaculture has been applied at the
community scale for more than a decade
it's also an area that includes
Schumacher College which has been
convening systems thinkers and doing
regional scale permaculture work going
back several decades that this is a
place where they have developed very
robust educational programs community
facilitation participation ecological
restoration and quite a lot that's
happening there so this area of totnes
and Devon in England is a place with
deep historical roots that people have
been doing work like this including
training people to the level of masters
degrees and PhD level work so if you're
familiar with the work being done now by
Daniel Christian fall
Daniel was trained at Schumacher College
has spent time at Fenn to him in the
community that's in Scotland connected
to this regional network that's larger
than what's happening in England that
spreads across the British Isles and so
you'd know that there's a lot of work
happening in that place now let me give
another example I've just started to
learn what the cha-cha people are doing
and have been doing in Peru for quite
some time
where there is a civilization that is
thousands of years old it goes way back
to the Incas and in some cases even
earlier where they built very complex
terraforming of terraces up in the
mountains so that on steep slopes they
could manage the canals and the the
water within the area to have very
robust agriculture while at the same
time creating very complex food forests
doing agro ecology work built up over
multiple generations of people to be
able to live with very complex society
over the span of several thousand years
some of that knowledge is still
maintained within the indigenous
communities that are up high in the
Andes and these people are working very
hard and have been for several decades
now to preserve their cultural knowledge
in the face of globalization and to
maintain a sufficient and sustainable
form of water management for their food
production systems as climate change is
melting away the ice that's up in the
glaciers of the mountains and
threatening their food supply by
threatening their water supply that
these people in the Andes in Peru and
extending into other areas in Chile
Argentina and you can look even further
at some of the work in Colombia Brazil
other parts of South America that this
place among the cha-cha people in Peru
has thousands of years of knowledge
maintained in their culture they are
working very hard to preserve their
water management and food management in
the Andes and they've been doing this
work in very rigorous ways for several
decades so just looking at these two
examples where as you dive in you would
quickly begin to learn that a huge
amount has already been done a huge
amount of activity is currently ongoing
and the coordination at regional scale
is at some level of maturity that is not
far enough that they need to go farther
and there are many other places that
aren't as far along as these two
examples I just named that need to get
to this level of maturity as quickly as
possible so in our work developing a
curriculum for the design of bioregions
from a regenerative point of view is
something that's desperately needed and
I'm getting to work with the
regenerative communities Network with
the University of International
Cooperation here in Costa Rica which is
connected to the biosphere reserves all
across Latin America and has a very
strong 25-year history of training
people in sustainable and regenerative
development using project management
approaches that we're looking at
to build an education program that
teaches people how to manage projects
for regeneration at the territorial
scale there are a lot of pieces to this
that I'll help bring out into the world
through the work that we're doing in the
coming weeks and months but for now I
just wanted to share a little bit of the
thinking about why we're thinking about
bioregions focusing on education and
capacity building for organizations as
hundreds possibly thousands of regional
scale projects begin to converge to try
to achieve planetary scale change in the
coming decades so reach out to me if
you'd like to get involved follow my
work or the work of any of the other
organizations in this space I would
highly recommend going to the
regenerative communities Network region
community's not net or regenerative
communities net login become a member
there and get active in what we're doing
and we will be rolling out this
education program in the coming months
we're trying to get this out as quickly
as we can because it's urgently needed
so watch this space there's going to be
a lot more coming